Omari Sharpe

Queens, NY | (718) 541-9276

osharpe001@gmail.com | osharpesportfolio.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/omarisharpe | https://qithub.com/OSharpe001

SUMMARY:

Detail-oriented web developer with strong analytical skills. Practical experience after college-level training with various programming languages. Resourceful with a solid grasp of technical skills, coding techniques and best practices. An adaptive frame of mind and extremely organized. Strong collaboration skills, diligent work ethics, and critical thinking capabilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages/Libraries:

PYTHON3 | JAVASCRIPT | HTML5 | CSS3 | REACT | NODE | EXPRESS | TERRAFORM | DJANGO | PHP

• Tools/Apparatus:

RESTFUL API | SQL & NOSQL | GIT & GITHUB | JSONWEBTOKENS | FIGMA | TRELLO | DISCORD | POSTMAN | MONGODB | MYSQL | SQLITE | POSTGRES | MAMP | NGROK

EDUCATION:

•	Per Scholas (Software Engineering Bootcamp) New York, NY	5/2023-9/2023		
	Certificate of Completion in Software Engineering	Honors: 100.75%		
•	Vaughn College of Aeronautics and Technology Queens, NY	9/1999-12/2004		
	Bachelor of Science in Aviation Maintenance	Honors: 3.62 GPA		

CERTIFICATES:

•	Meta Front-End Developer Coursera	3/11/2023
•	Web Applications for Everybody Coursera	6/27/2022
•	PostgreSQL for Everybody Coursera	5/10/2022
•	Python 3 Programming Coursera	4/29/2022
•	AWS Fundamentals Coursera	3/11/2022
•	Django for Everybody Coursera	2/28/2022
•	Python for Everybody Coursera	11/18/2021
•	JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Free Code Camp	10/31/2022
•	Responsive Web Design Free Code Camp	9/29/2022

PROJECTS:

 Dev Squared - Blogging App Created Utilizing: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, HTML and CSS https://devsquared-9dbdb24d78db.herokuapp.com/

9/6/2023 - Present

Anime Hunter - Anime Search App
 Created utilizing: React, JavaScript, API's, HTML and CSS
 https://animehunterguild.netlify.app

8/7/2023 - 8/13/2023

 Pokemon Memory Match Game - Game Created utilizing: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and a RESTful API https://osharpe001.github.io

6/29/2023 - 7/10/2023

Letter To Success - Game
 Created utilizing: React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
 https://lettertosuccess.netlify.app

2/2023 - 4/2023

Little Lemon Bistro - Online Shopping App Created utilizing: React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS https://littlelemonbistro.vercel.app

1/2023 - 2/2023

EMPLOYMENT:

Union Electrician | Thorn Electric | New York City, NY

10/2018 - 01/2021

- Wired fire alarm systems and devices, motors, and motor control apparatus for safety and operations
- Plotted and install raceway conduits, lighting fixtures, and other electrical devices
- Calculated total current load and paths of circuits to ensure proper operation of devices and safety
- Troubleshoot electrical issues to resolve hazardous and unsightly situations

Union Electrician | B & G Electric | New York City, NY

02/2018 - 10/2018

- Wired fire alarm systems and devices, motors, and motor control apparatus for safety and operations
- Plotted and install raceway conduits, lighting fixtures, and other electrical devices
- Calculated total current load and paths of circuits to ensure proper operation of devices and safety
- Troubleshoot electrical issues to resolve hazardous and unsightly situations

Union Electrician and Foreman | H & L Electric | New York City, NY

1/2013 - 11/2017

- Consulted with clients regarding current and future project parameters
- Executed timeline management to complete projects over 10% faster than the designated schedule
- Ensured productivity of managed coworkers and work quality and saved over 10% of the budget
- Fulfilled Electrician Duties (as stated in other companies above)

Union Electrician and Foreman | Mazza Electric | New York City, NY

07/1995 - 01/2013

- Became "youngest Foreman ever" in company's history (at 25yrs old), after rising from Electrical Helper
- Completed first job as Foreman 12% faster than projected estimates
- Conducted client consultations regarding future projects (taking on Project Manager responsibilities)
- Fulfilled Electrician Duties (as stated in other companies above)